Robert L. Cavalero

r.cavalero@comcast.net | 206.601.3046 | Seattle, Washington LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/robert-cavalero | Github https://github.com/rcavalero/portfolio

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER & BUSINESS ANALYST

Full-Stack Web Developer with extensive insurance business systems operations and analysis experience. Certified in Full-Stack web development from the University of Washington. Proven ability to solve problems and increase efficiency for the user experience. Bringing extensive knowledge of front office business experience to the web development process that includes configuring Agency Management Systems, managing databases, writing SQL based reports, managing business processes and creating advanced level Excel spreadsheets.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: SQL, Javascript, HTML, CSS

Development Tools: Express, Node.Js, React.js, JQuery, Bootstrap, Github, Handlebars, Heroku

Database: MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose, MS Access

Other: Microsoft Office Suite, Advanced MS Excel, MS Visio, MS Project, Crystal Reports, Infomaker,

Act, Adobe Acrobat Professional, ConceptOne, Salesforce, ImageRight, Duck Creek

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Business Process Improvement
- Business Process Mapping
- Management Reporting

- Advanced Excel (pivot tables, vlookup)
- Problem Solving
- Data Analysis

APPLICATIONS BUILT

WebGen2020

https://webgen2020.herokuapp.com/

- A management content system for the restaurant industry. Database Design and assisted with back-end development
- Front-end built using Handlebars and Materialize with MySQL and Sequelize used on the back-end.

SEEFOOD

https://seefood-app.herokuapp.com/

- A recipe book that utilizes augmented reality for a unique user experience. Database Design and back-end development.
- Front-end built using React.js with MySQL and Sequelize used on the back-end.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Distinguished Programs Senior Operations Specialist

Bellevue, WA 2015 to 2018

rcing (BPO)

Charged with managing the relationship with the Business Process Outsourcing (BPO) team in China.

Key Contributions:

- Led business units in the mapping of existing processes to identify opportunities for improvement, automation and/or outsourcing while transitioning to a new business management system
- Orchestrated transition of new / improved tasks with BPO
- Developed and monitored staffing budget for BPO

Fulcrum Insurance Programs (Acquired by Distinguished Programs in 2015) **Vice President of Operations**

Bellevue, WA 2011 to 2015

Owned responsibility for ensuring the optimal performance of information systems used for accounting, human resources, and office administration.

Key Contributions:

- Launched profit-driving strategies that increased revenue from \$1M to \$6M in fourvears.
- Pioneered use of new agency management system allowing office to track data, process transactions, manage accounts, and analyze reports through one streamlined platform.
- Coordinated the timely delivery of a variety of SQL based ad hoc reports and maintained them as required with the utmost attention to accuracy, precision, and efficiency.
- Created customized Excel rating spreadsheets to calculate premiums for various insurance programs including multi-layered, umbrella programs.

National Specialty Underwriters (Acquired by Distinguished Programs in 2015) **Director of Account Services - Hospitality**

Bellevue, WA

2007 to 2011

Analyzed key data to identify opportunities for streamlining processes, reducing redundancies, and improving staff performance.

Key Contributions:

- Decreased collections process by 30-days by automating accounts receivables.
- Designed file storage structure and implemented ImageRight as new document management system
- Created specifications for a time and expense billing system that allowed claims department to track allocated and unallocated expenses when eroding the SIR.

Additional experience with CertusClaims Administration, a subsidiary of National Specialty *Underwriters and Distinguished Programs*

EDUCATION

University of Washington

Seattle, WA

Certificate in Full-Stack Web Development

Feb 2020

An intensive 12 week program focused on gaining technical skills for Full-Stack Web Development